Lestoque, Albert; Papers ger059
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files, 1947-1960; 8; 230 file folders
  - Case files, Undated; 8.2
    - Lestoque wegen Entschädigung nach dem Bundesentschädigungsgesetz (B.E.G), 1953-1955 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 26)
    - Lestoque wegen Entschädigung nach dem Bundesentschädigungsgesetz (B.E.G), 1956-1957 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 27)
    - "Besprechung des Urteils des B.G.H. Karlsruhe", 1958; manuscript (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 28)
    - Lestoque/Leser/Lingemann vs. Deutsches Reich -- Albert Lestoque's notes, Undated (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 29)
    - Lestoque/Leser/Lingemann vs. Deutsches Reich, 1950-1952 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 30)
    - Lestoque/Leser/Lingemann vs. Deutsches Reich, 1953 (Box 10 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 31)
    - Lestoque/Leser/Lingemann vs. Deutsches Reich, 1954 (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 1)
    - Lestoque/Leser/Lingemann vs. Deutsches Reich, 1955 (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 2)
    - Lestoque/Leser/Lingemann vs. Deutsches Reich- Petition for Review, 1955 August 12 (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 3)
    - Lestoque/Leser/Lingemann vs. Deutsches Reich, 1956-1961 (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 4)
    - Lestoque vs. das Land Nordrhein-Westfalen, 1938; 1957-1960 (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 5)
    - Erben Leser vs. Blatzheim, Moll, Krahé, Zindel, Leyer, Geulich -- general files, 1952 (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 6)
    - Erben Leser vs. Blatzheim, Moll, Krahé, Zindel, Leyer -- Otto Wuttke files, 1953-1954 (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 7)
    - Erben Leser vs. Blatzheim -- background materials, Undated (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 8)
    - Erben Leser vs. Blatzheim -- notes, Undated (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 9)
    - Erben Leser vs. Blatzheim, 1941-1949 (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 10)
    - Erben Leser vs. Blatzheim, 1950-1951 (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 11)
    - Erben Leser vs. Blatzheim, 1952 (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 12)
    - Erben Leser vs. Blatzheim, 1953 (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 13)
    - Erben Leser vs. Blatzheim, 1954 (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 14)
    - Erben Leser vs. Blatzheim, 1955-1956 (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 15)
    - Erben Leser vs. Blatzheim, 1957-1960 (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 16)
    - Erben Leser vs. Blatzheim, 1961-1963 (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 17)
    - Erben Leser vs. Geulich, 1951-1955 (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 18)
    - Erben Leser vs. Karl Hermann (Waffensammlung), 1950-1952 (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 19)
    - Erben Leser vs. Krahé, 1949-1954 (Box 11 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 20)
    - Erben Leser vs. Leyer, 1950-1954 (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 1)
    - Erben Leser vs. Moll, 1950-1954 (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 2)
    - Erben Leser vs. Zindel -- Zindel Grundstücksverhandlung, 1931-1936 (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 3)
    - Erben Leser vs. Zindel -- Zindel Grundstücksverhandlung, 1941-1942 (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 4)
    - Erben Leser vs. Zindel, 1950-1951 (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 5)
    - Erben Leser vs. Zindel, 1952-1953 (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 6)
    - Erben Leser vs. Zindel, 1954-1958 (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 7)
    - Leser Family foundation -- Lestoque/Leser/Lingemann disputes, 1940s (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 8)
    - Leser vs. Lestoque, 1950 (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 9)
    - Leser vs. Lestoque -- Sale of property at 1585 Monaco Parkway, Denver, CO, 1950 (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 10)
    - Leser family foundation -- Albert Lestoque's accounts, Undated (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 11)
    - Lestoque vs. Dackweiler (Neunier), Volkermann, 1948-1957 (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 12)
    - Lestoque vs. Dackweiler, Volermann, 1958-1961 (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 13)
    - Lestoque vs. Margarete Neunier, Martha Volkermann (Otto Wuttke files), 1954-1955 (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 14)
    - Lestoque vs. Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft, 1951-1952 (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 15)
    - Lestoque vs. Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft, 1953 (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 16)
    - Lestoque vs. Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft, 1954 January-1954 June (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 17)
    - Lestoque vs. Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft, 1954 July-1954 December (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 18)
    - Lestoque vs. Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft, 1955 (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 19)
    - Lestoque vs. Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft, 1956 (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 20)
    - Lestoque vs. Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft, 1957 (Box 12 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 21)
    - Lestoque vs. Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (Otto Wuttke files), 1952-1954 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 1)
    - Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft -- clippings, Undated (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 2)
    - Lestoque vs. Enskat, 1951-1956 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 3)
    - Erben Leser vs. Fussangel, 1951; 1954 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 4)
    - Erben Leser vs. Hotel Dreesen, 1950-1951 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 5)
    - Lestoque vs. Firma Klöckner & Co., 1950-1956 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 6)
    - Lestoque vs. Firma Klöckner & Co. (Otto Wuttke files), 1953 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 7)
    - Nöller, Hans (Notar) -- correspondence, 1951-1956 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 8)
    - Lestoque vs. Nöller, 1959-1960 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 9)
    - Leser vs. Rheinisches Landesmuseum (A. von Jordans), 1949-1951 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 10)
    - Lestoque vs. Ruhrgas Aktiengesellschaft, 1950-1955 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 11)
    - Lestoque vs. Ruhrgas Aktiengesellschaft (Otto Wuttke files), 1950-1954 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 12)
    - Erben Leser vs. Schumacher, 1950-1955 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 13)
    - Erben Leser vs. Schumacher, 1956-1958 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 14)
    - Erben Leser vs. Schumacher, 1961-1962 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 15)
    - Erben Leser vs. Schumacher (Otto Wuttke files), 1952-1954 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 16)
    - Lestoque vs. Städtische Sparkasse, 1951-1953 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 17)
    - Lestoque vs. Städtische Sparkasse (Otto Wuttke files), 1951-1953 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 18)
    - Lestoque vs. Westdeutscher Verein zur Forderung der Christengemeinschaft, 1951-1954 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 19)
    - Lestoque vs. Westdeutscher Verein zur Forderung der Christengemeinschaft, 1955-1961 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 20)
    - Endemann, Harald -- correspondence, 1951 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 21)
    - Endemann, Harald -- correspondence, 1952 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 22)
    - Endemann vs. Lestoque, 1953-1954 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 23)
    - Endemann vs. Lestoque, 1955 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 24)
    - Leinen vs. Lestoque, 1955-1960 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 25)
    - Lummert vs. Lestoque, 1956-1959 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 26)
    - Menden vs. Lingemann, 1951-1953 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 27)
    - Thiele vs. Lingemann, 1957-1959 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 28)
    - Wuttke, Otto -- correspondence, 1952-1954 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 29)
    - Wuttke vs. Lestoque, 1956 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 30)
    - Gesellschaft "Neues Heim" -- correspondence (Otto Wuttke files), 1953 (Box 13 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 31)
  - Correspondence re: restitution matters with U.S. officials, occupation force (HICOG) officials, Undated; 8.3
    - Allott, Gordon, 1955-1960 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 1)
    - Beecher, Charles H., 1956 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 2)
    - Bishop, Neal, 1952-1960 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 3)
    - British Embassy (K. D. Jamieson), 1948-1951 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 4)
    - Burdick, Usher, 1955-1956; clippings (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 5)
    - Carroll, John A., 1959-1960 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 6)
    - Carroll, John A. -- clippings, Undated (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 7)
    - Conant, James B., 1954; clippings (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 8)
    - Department of State, 1946-1951 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 9)
    - Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States, 1956-1957 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 10)
    - Hardin, Hess & Eder (Monroe H. Collenburg), 1946-1949 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 11)
    - House Documents Room, 1955 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 12)
    - Johnson, Edwin C., 1947-1949 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 13)
    - Johnson, Edwin C., 1950-1954 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 14)
    - Johnson, Edwin C. -- clippings, Undated (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 15)
    - Keating, Kenneth B., 1960 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 16)
    - Kelly, Morgan J. P. (HICOG), 1953 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 17)
    - Kirkpatrick, Sir Ivone, United Kingdom High Commissioner in Germany, 1952-1953 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 18)
    - Lennon, Jack H. (HICOG), 1951-1954 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 19)
    - McCloy, John J. (HICOG), 1951 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 20)
    - Millikin, Eugene D., 1948-1953 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 21)
    - Millikin, Eugene D. -- clippings, Undated (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 22)
    - National Archives, 1948 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 23)
    - Pearce, Charles C., 1956 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 24)
    - Priest, J. Percy (re: Bill H.R. 5840), 1955 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 25)
    - Rogers, Byron G., 1951-1956 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 26)
    - Rogers, Byron G., 1957-1960 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 27)
    - Rogers, Byron G. -- clippings, Undated (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 28)
  - Clippings on restitution and post-war Germany, Undated; 8.4
    - Restitution, post-war Germany -- clippings, 1944-1946 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 29)
    - Restitution, post-war Germany -- clippings, 1947 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 30)
    - Restitution, post-war Germany -- clippings, 1948 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 31)
    - Restitution, post-war Germany -- clippings, 1949 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 32)
    - Restitution, post-war Germany -- clippings, 1950 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 33)
    - Restitution, post-war Germany -- clippings, 1951 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 34)
    - Restitution, post-war Germany -- clippings, 1952 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 35)
    - Restitution, post-war Germany -- clippings, 1953 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 36)
    - Restitution, post-war Germany -- clippings, 1954 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 37)
    - Restitution, post-war Germany -- clippings, 1955 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 38)
    - Restitution, post-war Germany -- clippings, 1956 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 39)
    - Restitution, post-war Germany -- clippings, 1957 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 40)
    - Restitution, post-war Germany -- clippings, 1958 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 41)
    - Restitution, post-war Germany -- clippings, 1959 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 42)
    - Restitution, post-war Germany -- clippings, 1960 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 43)
  - U.S. War damage bills; U.S. government publications, Undated; 8.5
    - War Damage Bills, 1955 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 44)
    - Bill H.R. 5840, 1955 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 45)
    - Bill H. R. 9864, 1956 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 46)
    - War Damage Bills, 1956-1958 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 47)
    - War Damage Bills, 1959-1960 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 48)
    - U.S. government publications on compensation claims, 1956-1958 (Box 14 (8-Wiedergutmachung (Restitution) files), Folder 49)
- Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues, Undated; 9; 19 file folders
  This series contains miscellaneous materials, as well as a number of periodicals dealing with restitution and emigration issues. Many of the periodicals contain articles pertinent to Lestoque's restitution claims and are marked and annotated by him. One item of interest is a copy of the December 1939 issue of Klaus Mann's Decision, which was devoted to Exiled German Authors. Twelve of the articles have been signed by their respective émigré authors.
  - Direction, vol. 2, No. 8, 1939 December (Box 14 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 50)
    Original issue dedicated to Exiled German Writers, with articles autographed by Wieland Herzfelde, Thomas Mann, Curt Riess, Oskar Maria Graf, Paul Tillich, Ferdinand Bruckner, Ernst Bloch, Raoul Auernheimer, Friedrich Alexan, Manfred Georg, Klaus Mann and Walter Schoenstedt.
  - Report of the O'Sullivan Committee on the progress made in the disposal of internal restitution claims in the British Zone of Germany, 30 June 1951 (Box 14 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 51)
    London: His Majesty's Stationery Office, 1951.
  - Sears, Edwin M. "Correlation of Power, Policy and Law in International Relations (The Problem of Dumbarton Oakes)", ca. 1945; reprint (Box 14 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 52)
  - Art topics -- clippings, Undated (Box 14 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 53)
  - Deutscher Bundestag materials, Undated (Box 14 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 54)
  - Periodical issues, Undated; 9.6
    - Die Anklage. Organ der entrechteten Nachkriegsgeschädigten, scattered issues, 1954-1955 (Box 15 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 1)
    - Bundesgesetzblatt, scattered issues, 1952-1957 (Box 15 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 2)
    - The Insider. Ed. Charles Hodges, Johannes Steel, 1939 February 28-1939 April 25 (Box 15 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 3)
    - International Committee for the Study of European Questions, No. 1-6, 1947-1948 (Box 15 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 4)
    - International Committee for the Study of European Questions, No. 7-11, 1948-1949 (Box 15 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 5)
    - International Committee for the Study of European Questions, No. 12-15, 1949-1950 (Box 15 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 6)
    - Monatsschrift für Deutsches Recht, scattered issues, Undated (Box 15 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 7)
    - Official Gazette of the Allied High Commission for Germany, scattered issues, 1947; 1950 (Box 15 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 8)
    - PS. Press Service of the German American Writers Assn, No. 5-9, Undated (Box 15 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 9)
    - Rechtsprechung zum Wiedergutmachungsrecht, scattered issues, 1950-1960 (Box 15 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 10)
    - Die Restitution, 1950-1951 (Box 15 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 11)
    - Die Restitution, 1952 (Box 15 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 12)
    - Die Restitution, 1953-1954 (Box 15 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 13)
    - Service d'Archives, 1937-1938 (Box 15 (9-Miscellaneous materials; periodical issues), Folder 14)